# **Daehwa Kim**

407 South Craig Street, Pittsburgh, PA 15213 daehwak@cs.cmu.edu • +1 415 937 4111 • https://daehwa.github.io

#### RESEARCH INTERESTS

My recent research explores the intersection of Human-Computer Interaction, Sensing, and Machine Learning, particularly on transforming antenna systems into advanced interface technologies. I enhance wireless sensing capabilities to improve machine perception, focusing on tracking of the human body, hand, and mouth poses as new input paradigms of spatial computing. I interned at Apple ML Research (2024) and Meta Reality Labs (2023). I presented papers at ACM CHI, UIST, and ISS, and have received two Best Paper Honorable Mention awards at CHI.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Ph.D. student, Carnegie Mellon University, School of Computer Science,

Sep 2022 – Current

**Human-Computer Interaction Institute** 

Advised by Prof. Chris Harrison at Future Interfaces Group

# M.Sc., KAIST, School of Computing

Mar 2019 – Feb 2021

- Advised by Prof. Geehyuk Lee at Human-Computer Interaction Lab
- Graduated with 2020 Best Thesis Award

# B.S., UNIST, Electrical and Computer Engineering

Mar 2015 – Feb 2019

- Computer Science and Engineering (Major) and Electrical Engineering (Minor)
- Entered with top honors.
- Summer session program, University of the Arts London, London, UK

Jul 2018

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Apple ML Research, Cupertino, CA

May 2024 - Aug 2024

- Research Intern
- Manager: Mario Srouji and Jian Zhang

### Meta Reality Labs, Redmond, WA

May 2023 – Aug 2023

- Research Scientist Intern
- Manager: Eric Whitmire

# Future Interfaces Group, Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA

Sep 2021 – Apr 2022

- Research Associate, Human-Computer Interaction Institute
- Advisor: Chris Harrison

# KAIST HCI Lab, Daejeon

Mar 2018 – Jun 2018

- Undergraduate Research Student, School of Computing
- Advisor: Geehyuk Lee

#### Hyper-connected Communication Research Laboratory, ETRI

Jan 2018 – Mar 2018

Research Intern

# AWARDS & HONORS

#### Best Paper Honorable Mention Award, ACM CHI 2022

May 2022

 Craig Shultz, <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Karan Ahuja, and Chris Harrison, "TriboTouch: Micro-Patterned Surfaces for Low Latency Touchscreens" in *Proceedings of the 2022 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, New Orleans, LA, USA, Apr 2022.

# Best Paper Honorable Mention Award, ACM CHI 2021

May 2021

<u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee, "AtaTouch: Robust Finger Pinch Detection for a VR Controller Using RF Return Loss" in *Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, Yokohama, Japan.

# Best Master's Thesis Award, KAIST School of Computing

Feb 2021

■ Thesis: "OddEyeCam: Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interaction Using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras"

#### Uni-Star Scholarship, UNIST

Mar 2015 - Feb 2019

■ Tuition + academic funding every semester for the top rank in entrance exam

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

- [1] <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Vimal Mollyn, Chris Harrison, "WorldPoint: Finger Pointing as a Rapid and Natural Trigger for In-The-Wild Mobile Interactions" in *Proceedings of the 2023 ACM International Conference on Interactive Surfaces and Spaces*, Pittsburgh, USA, Nov 2023.
- [2] <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Chris Harrison, "Pantœnna: Mouth Pose Estimation for VR/AR Headsets Using Low-Profile Antenna and Impedance Characteristic Sensing" in *Proceedings of the 36th Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology*, San Francisco, USA, Oct 2023.
- [3] Hui-Shyong Yeo, Erwin Wu, <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Juyoung Lee, Hyung-il Kim, Seo Young Oh, Luna Takagi, Woontack Woo, Hideki Koike, and Aaron J Quigley, "OmniSense: Exploring Novel Input Sensing and Interaction Techniques on Mobile Device with Omni-Directional Camera" in *Proceedings of the 2023 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, Hamburg, Germany, Apr 2023.
- [4] <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, and Chris Harrison, "EtherPose: Continuous Hand Pose Tracking with Wrist-Worn Antenna Impedance" in *Proceedings of the 35th Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology*, Bend, Oregon, USA, Oct 2022.
- [5] Craig Shultz, <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Karan Ahuja, and Chris Harrison, "TriboTouch: Micro-Patterned Surfaces for Low Latency Touchscreens" in *Proceedings of the 2022 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, New Orleans, LA, USA, Apr 2022. <u>Best Paper Honorable Mention Award</u>; <u>Top 5%</u>
- [6] <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee, "AtaTouch: Robust Finger Pinch Detection for a VR Controller Using RF Return Loss" in *Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, Yokohama, Japan. <u>Best Paper Honorable Mention Award</u>; Top 5%
- [7] <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee, "OddEyeCam: A Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interaction Using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras" in *Proceedings of the 33rd Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology*, Virtual Event, USA, Oct 2020.
- [8] Keunwoo Park, <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Seongkook Heo, and Geehyuk Lee, "MagTouch: Robust Finger Identification for a Smartwatch Using a Magnet Ring and a Built-in Magnetometer" in *Proceedings of the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, Honolulu, Hawaii, USA, Apr 2020.

### ACADEMIC SERVICE

### Reviewer

CHI '24, IMWUT '23, SIGGRAPH '23 Poster, UIST '23, CHI '23, UIST '22, CHI '22 LBW, IMWUT '21, CHI '21 LBW